deepdyve.com 2014-11-12

# About DeepDyve | DeepDyve

Last Updated 3/3/2014

DeepDyve, Inc. (“DeepDyve”) knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. By visiting DeepDyve’s website at [http://www.deepdyve.com](http://www.deepdyve.com/) (“deepdyve.com”), or using any of our services or products, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy.

Deepdyve Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, http://www.deepdyve.com. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [support@deepdyve.com](mailto:support@deepdyve.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can [contact TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

## WHAT DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVER?

This Privacy Policy covers DeepDyve’s treatment of personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") DeepDyve gathers when you are accessing deepdyve.com and when you use our services. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that DeepDyve does not own or control, or to individuals DeepDyve does not employ or manage. 

## WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DOES DEEPDYVE DISPLAY OR COLLECT?

The information we gather from users enables us to personalize and improve our services, and to allow our users to set up a user account and profile. We collect the following types of information from our users. 

## PERSONAL INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE TO US: 

We receive and store any information you enter on deepdyve.com or provide to us in any other way. The types of Personal Information collected may include your name, e-mail address, billing address, credit card information, information about your use of the services on deepdyve.com. You may choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of our special features. The Personal Information you provide is used for such purposes as responding to your requests for certain information, products and services, newsletters, billing you for goods and services, provide you an API key, sign up for search alerts regarding articles, view your transaction history, customizing the advertising and content you see, and communicating with you about specials and new features. 

If you choose to use our Invite a Colleague feature on our site, we will ask you for your Colleague’s name and email address. We will automatically send your colleague a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. DeepDyve stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. 

Your colleague may contact us at [support@deepdyve.com](mailto:support@deepdyve.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

## PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY:

  * We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with deepdyve.com or obtain services from us. DeepDyve automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, DeepDyve cookie information, and the page you requested. We also record the details of your transactions in an anonymous form on deepdyve.com.
  * Generally, our service automatically collects usage information, such as the numbers and frequency of visitors to our site and its components, similar to TV ratings that indicate how many people watched a particular show. DeepDyve only uses this data in aggregate form, that is, as a statistical measure, and not in a manner that would identify you personally. This type of aggregate data enables us to figure out how often users use parts of deepdyve.com or services so that we can make deepdyve.com appealing to as many users as possible, and improve those services. As part of this use of information, we may provide aggregate information to our partners about how our users, collectively, use our site. We share this type of statistical data so that our partners also understand how often people use their services and deepdyve.com, so that they, too, may provide you with an optimal online experience. Again, DeepDyve never discloses aggregate information to a partner in a manner that would identify you personally.
  * Facebook Connect: Deepdyve allows users to access Facebook Connect to interact with friends and share on Facebook through Wall and friends’ news feeds. If you are already logged into Deepdyve and Facebook, when you click on “Connect with Facebook” you will be prompted to merge your profiles. If you are already logged into Deepdyve but not logged into Facebook, when you click on “Connect with Facebook” you will be prompted to merge your profiles. If you are already logged into Deepdyve but not logged into Facebook, when you click on “Connect with Facebook” you will be prompted to enter your Facebook credentials or to “Sign up for Facebook.” By proceeding, you are allowing Deepdyve.com to access your information and you are agreeing to the Facebook Terms of Use in your use of Deepdyve.com.

Conversely, if you are not currently registered as a DeepDyve user and you click on “Sign in using Facebook,” you will first be asked to enter your Facebook credentials and then be given the option to register and join DeepDyve You have the option disable Facebook Connect at any time by logging into”My Profile” and clicking on “My Facebook Profile”. Further, you can edit privacy settings for the reviews that appear on Facebook or disconnect this service by visiting the Facebook Application Settings page. 

## E-MAIL COMMUNICATIONS: 

We often receive a confirmation when you open an e-mail from DeepDyve if your computer supports this type of program. DeepDyve uses this confirmation to help us make e-mails more interesting and helpful. We also compare our user list to lists received from other companies, in an effort to avoid sending unnecessary messages to our users. 

## PUBLIC FORUMS:

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@deepdyve.com](mailto:support@deepdyve.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

## SURVEYS:

From time to time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in a survey on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The request information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use this information to monitor site traffic and personalize the site. 

We may use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys; that company is prohibited from using our users’ personally for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice. 

## WHAT ABOUT COOKIES?

  * Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and tell us how and when pages in our site are visited and by how many people. Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. We strongly recommend that you leave the cookies activated, however, because cookies enable you to take advantage of some of deepdyve.com's most attractive features. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.
  * Our service providers use both session ID and persistent cookies to make it easier for you to use our site. The use of cookies by our service providers is not covered by our privacy policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our third party partners employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help them better manage content on our site. We tie the information gathered to our Customers’ or Users’ personally identifiable information. 
  * Ads appearing on deepdyve.com may be delivered to users by our advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies will allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile demographic information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy policy covers the use of cookies by DeepDyve and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. [To opt-out from receiving third party targeted ads please click here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/).

## WILL DEEPDYVE SHARE ANY OF THE PERSONAL INFORMATION IT RECEIVES?

Personal Information about our users is an integral part of our business. We do not share, sell, rent or trade your Personal Information with third parties other than as disclosed within this privacy policy. 

## AFFILIATED BUSINESSES WE DO NOT CONTROL:

We may become affiliated with a variety of businesses and work closely with them. In certain situations, these businesses may operate stores at deepdyve.com or sell items to you through deepdyve.com. In other situations, DeepDyve may provide services, or sell products jointly with affiliated businesses. You can easily recognize when an affiliated business is associated with your transaction, and we will share user information that is related to such transactions with that affiliated business. It will be clear at the time you provide your personal information as to which privacy policy will govern the collection and use of your information. 

## AGENTS:

We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you. Examples include sending email, analyzing data, processing payments, and providing user services. Unless we tell you differently, DeepDyve’s agents do not have any right to use Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. You hereby consent to our sharing of Personal Information for the above purposes. 

We may also share your personal information in the following situations:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, 

## USER PROFILES:

User profile information including user ID, zip code and country may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within deepdyve.com. Users’ full names will not be directly revealed to other users by DeepDyve, however, to facilitate searching User Submissions, DeepDyve allows users to search for other users by using first and last name and other information users provide in their profile. 

## COMMUNICATION IN RESPONSE TO USER SUBMISSIONS:

As part of deepdyve.com and Services, you may receive from DeepDyve and other users e-mail and other communication relating to your User Submissions. You acknowledge and agree that by posting such User Submissions, DeepDyve and other users may send you e-mail and other communication that they determine in their sole discretion relate to your User Submissions. 

## PROMOTIONAL OFFERS AND NEWSLETTERS:

We may send offers to certain users on behalf of other businesses or ourselves. However, when we do so, we do not give the other business your name and address. You may also sign up to receive our newsletters. If you do not wish to receive these offers, please send us an email to unsubscribe at [support@deepdyve.com](mailto:support@deepdyve.com) or utilize the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each email communication

## BUSINESS TRANSFERS:

In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if DeepDyve, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that DeepDyve goes out of business or enters bankruptcy. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

## PROTECTION OF DEEPDYVE AND OTHERS:

We may release Personal Information to enforce or apply our Terms of Service and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of DeepDyve, our employees, our users, or others. This includes, without limitation, exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection. 

## WITH YOUR CONSENT:

Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be given the option to prevent the sharing of this information. 

## IS PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT ME SECURE?

Your DeepDyve account Personal Information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. You need ensure that there is no unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.   
DeepDyve follows generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.. For additional information about the security measures DeepDyve uses in connection with deepdyve.com, please contact us at [security_policy@deepdyve.com](mailto:security_policy@deepdyve.com). deepdyve.com contains links to other sites. 

When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

DeepDyve is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When linking to another site a user should read the privacy policy stated on that site. This Privacy Policy only governs information collected on deepdyve.com.   
Please be aware that whenever you voluntarily post information to public areas on deepdyve.com or any other public forums, such information can be accessed by the public. 

Our Web site also includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION CAN I ACCESS?

You may correct, update or remove your personal information at any time by logging into your account and accessing the account settings feature or by emailing us at [support@deepdyve.com](mailto:support@deepdyve.com).   
Currently you may access and update the following information: 

  * Account Information (such as name, email address and billing information)
  * User profile (you may update your profile at any time which includes some of your account information and any other information you choose to share)
  * User preferences (you decide who see’s and does not see your profile, and who is able to message you)
  * Search History (you are able to edit any searches that you may have performed while using the site) 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [support@deepdyve.com](mailto:support@deepdyve.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

## WHAT OTHER CHOICES DO I HAVE?

  * As stated previously, you can always opt not to disclose information, even though it may be needed to take advantage of certain DeepDyve features.
  * You are able to add or update certain information on pages, such as those listed in the “What Personal Information Can I Access” section above. When you update information, however, we often maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records.
  * You may request deactivation of your account and deletion of personally identifiable information in your account by sending an e-mail to [support@deepdyve.com](mailto:support@deepdyve.com). Please note that when your personally identifiable information is deleted we no longer have the availability to send you information or payments. Additionally, some of your information may remain in our records after deactivation of your account. 

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY:

DeepDyve may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time for any reason. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used or collected. If we make material changes or in the way we use Personal Information, we will notify you via e-mail or by posting an announcement on deepdyve.com prior to the changes becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS:

If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy at deepdyve.com, please send us a detailed message to [privacy_policy@deepdyve.com](mailto:privacy_policy@deepdyve.com).

DeepDyve Inc.  
2221 Broadway St.  
Redwood City, CA 94063
